Mounish S

Powertrain Embedded Software Technical Analyst

More than 8 years of experience in the automotive industry, Involved in powertrain model-based software development, engine calibration, Vehicle testing, and validation in the engineering field. I am looking for new challenging projects and responsibilities and utilize the my skills for the development of the organization.

mounishsdm@gmail.com

9894744712

.

Chennai, India



linkedin.com/in/mounishsdm

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Analyst

Renault Nissan Technology Business Centre India

04/2022 - Present

Chennai, India

Roles and responsibilities

- Developed and implemented powertrain control algorithms for OBD functions using model-based development methodologies such as MATLAB/Simulink.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements and translate them into software specifications for powertrain control modules [ICE, Hybrid engines.]
- Designed and optimized control strategies for OBD monitors.
- Software V cycle process from SW high level design, low level design, MILs, HILs validation and verification.
- Documented software designs, implementation details, test plans, and results according to internal standards and regulatory requirements.
- Worked as Team lead for OBD function and achieved all deliverables on time and achieved the good customer feedbacks based on CSSR.

Deputy Senior EngineerDelphi-TVS Technologies Ltd

06/2019 - Present

Chennai, India

Roles and Responsibilities

- Had responsibility for the calibration of fault management (OBD) based on control strategy, testing, and validation in test bench and vehicle.
- Had responsibility for Vehicle Drivability Calibration, Drivability Assessment at various altitude trails and Support for vehicle drivability related requirements at all driving conditions.
- Supporting for the calibration of Common rail fuel injection system, Air charge management system (Throttle, EGR, sensors), and Aftertreatment system (LNT, DPF, SCR) to achieve the BS6 emission legislation.
- Supporting different high altitude-based calibrations and vehicle drivability testing and responsible for UDS service calibration.

Testing Engineer

Jeyam Automotive Pvt Ltd

11/2018 - 06/2019

Hyderabad, India

Roles and Responsibilities

- Worked as Testing engineer for prototype development for Engine Testing and Validation of product lifetime analysis.
- Handled the test bed maintenance, Testing protocol, Engine oil consumption, Engine service activity, Blow by check, smoke analysis.

Application Engineer Stanadyne India Pvt Ltd

12/2015 - 11/2018

Chennai. India

Roles and Responsibilities

- Worked as a test engineer for prototype development for fuel injection pump and Injector product development.
- Calibrated Diesel Rotary fuel pump for the Tractors and Generators application with the various power rating, performance, and emission standards.

SKILLS

Matlab, Simulink & State Flow

dSPACE & Reactis

ETAS INCA / MDA

MS office

Silverscan / GST OBD tool

DDT 2000 / Engine Calibration

PROJECTS

Force Motors FM2.6 (07/2019 - 07/2021)

Mahindra - BMT (07/2021 - 04/2022)

Nissan Motor Limited (04/2022 - Present)

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administrative Anna University, CEG Campus

01/2021 - 08/2023

Bachelor of Engineering - Mech Sri Krishna College of Technology

05/2011 - 05/2015 8.12 CGPA

ACHIEVEMENTS

Career achievements

Completion of FM2.6CR BS-VI Phase 1 calibration on time and achieved Legislative emission certification. Completed various altitude trails (Leh, Ooty). Developed the new control logic strategic for Euro7 regulations [On board monitoring].

Certification

Achieved Local Technical Leader [LTL] for OBD certified by Nissan Technical Centre, Japan.

HONOR AWARDS

GM Award

Awarded as best team for reducing the thermostat monitor false error detection for North America Projects.

INTERESTS

Badminton

Bike Riding